About	
Bio	
Services	
Contact

Lindsay Kramer
Licensed Independent Clinical Social Worker

BIO

I am a clinical therapist providing brief, solution-focused therapy and long-term  
psychotherapy for adults and children. I also provide counseling for families. I  
work with people to address a broad range of concerns including depression,  
anxiety, behavioral problems, relationship & identity issues, life transitions, anger,  
and trauma.

I have helped families negotiate life changes and adjustments and the negative  
behaviors that can be a result of those changes. I create a comfortable and safe  
relationship where vulnerable issues can be explored and understood together.

I am licensed by the state of Nebraska as a Licensed Independent Clinical Social  
Worker and Master Social Worker. I hold a Master's Degree in Social Work from  
Loyola University Chicago and a Master's Degree in Child Development from the  
Erikson Institute and have been working as a therapist since 2004.

ABOUT

It can be troubling to think that you have a problem you can not control or handle yourself. It can be worrisome to  
think that you or your child is going down a behavioral path that will be difficult to change. It can be extremely  
stressful to have feelings of low self-worth or thoughts of harming yourself. These are just a few examples of  
situations in which professional mental health therapy is necessary.

Taking the first step to seek help with your life concerns can be confusing and challenging. As a therapist, I under-
stand that it takes a giant of leap of faith to trust a stranger with the most important and often most painful areas of  
your life. The purpose of this website is to answer some of the most common questions that you might have about  
psychotherapy and to help you decide if I might be a good fit for you in your search for support.

My belief is that you can grow, heal, and transform-no matter how intense or difficult your experiences have been.  
We will work together to create a comfortable and safe relationship where vulnerable issues can be explored and  
understood together.

*Insurance accepted: Blue Cross Blue Shield, Tricare, Medicaid, Medicare

SERVICES

Our first meeting will consist of answering questions about yourself, your family, your history, and what you see as  
the problem or problems you would like to address. I will provide HIPPA and Informed Consent and answer any  
questions you may have for me. We will discuss whether you've met with a counselor or therapist before and what  
was helpful or not.

In the first few meetings together we will talk about what the problem is, what you have already done to address it,  
and we will discuss goals for therapy. This is a chance for us to get to know each other and establish a working  
relationship.

Methods

I will utilize several methods of therapy depending on your specific needs including solution focused, cognitive  
behavioral, and/or psychotherapy. What does that mean? Depending on what your goals for therapy are, and what  
you would like to discuss during our sessions, I will utilize different types of therapy.

Solution-focused brief therapy focuses mostly on what you would like to accomplish rather than the problems that  
brought you into therapy. This style of therapy focuses mostly on looking to the future you would like to create and  
mapping out the steps you need to take to get there.

Cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) focuses on replacing negative or destructive thoughts and behaviors with more  
positive ones. The belief with CBT is that changing the way you think about about a problem will change the way  
you cope with that problem.

Psychodynamic psychotherapy is usually a longer treatment period where your past experiences are explored and  
discussed. Our relationship will become more deeply developed and strengthened. In the context of our relation- 
ship we can identify the patterns of behavior or thinking that are likely causing the identified problem.

Regardless of what type of therapy is utilized to meet your specific needs, below are a few things you can  
expect in each meeting:
I will create a comfortable and safe relationship where vulnerable issues can be explored and understood together.  
My style is down to earth, thoughtful, and touched with humor.
I am direct and collaborative, and I focus on your strengths, resources, and goals in therapy.  
I believe strongly in each person's potential for becoming more fully who they wish to be.

CONTACT

Lindsay Kramer, Mental Health Therapy & Counseling
415 E 23rd St.
(402) 909-2787

Be the first to review  
View on Google Maps
Save

Send Me an E-Mail

*All information will be kept confidential.